Muhamad Nasih Ulwan Bin Ahmad Fauzee

Sungai Buloh, Selangor, Malaysia

muhamadnasih38@gmail.com

0194421514

linkedin.com/in/muhamad-nasih-ulwan-bin-ahmadfauzee-732290144

Summary

Spirited software engineer with 6 years of experience. Have a passion for developing innovative programs thathelp facilitate organizational success. Well-versed in technology such as Asp.net, .NET Core, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript. Critical thinker, and innovative creator to develop software that is customized to meet a company'sorganizational needs.

Experience



bood Fullstack Developer

ABOD Technology Services

May 2023 - Mar 2024 (11 months)

- · Collaborated with cross functional teams including business analyst to implement new features and resolve issues.
- Integrated third-party system and API such as Twilio to extend functionality.
- Developed new features and maintained for backoffice and customer-site application using Next JS, Angular, .NET Core and SQL Server.
- Developed Rest APIs using .NET Core.
- Implement lazy loading and paging that increase application performance.
- · Conducted code reviews and implemented best practices to ensure code quality and maintainability.
- Maintain and fix bugs on DNN(DotNetNuke) CMS, Next js and Angular.
- Create SQL Server store procedure and sql sequence.
- Collaborated with team members using Jira to ensure successful completion of projects.

Environment: Visual Studio, .NET framework, .NET Core, Typescript, C#, LINQ, HTML, JavaScript, Angular, React, Jira, SQL, Git Lab, Dbeaver Db, Docker, Jenkins.

🚫 Senior System Engineer

Fujitsu

Sep 2021 - May 2023 (1 year 9 months)

- Maintain, fix bugs and warning for windows application using vb.net.
- Conducted code reviews ensuring code quality and compliance with industry standards.
- Built a functional web application using SAP Fiori and SAP S4, using SAP UI5.
- Developed SAP ETO application using MVC Java and JavaScript and performed rigorous unit testing to identify and fix any bugs or errors.
- Developed windows application and batch file using WindowsForm, Batch Script and C#, alsoperformed manual testing and integration testing.
- Joined Anaplan Power BI as a model builder, manage to get level 1, level 2, level 3 modelbuilder certificate.
- · Promoted to supervisor system engineer due to strong performance and organizational impact.

Software Engineer

Dynisco

Feb 2019 - Sep 2021 (2 years 8 months)

- Played key role in feature implementation and enhancement, code refactoring and defect fixing.
- Implement Data Access Layer, Service Layer as part of the n layer architecture.
- Plan and develop end to end an automated chat bot system using Bot Framework, LUIS, QnA Maker and Azure Blob that allow customer asking related to company products.
- Manage data set on QnA Maker and train model on Microsoft Language Understanding(LUIS)
- Design and developed chatbot logging system and allow user to perform CRUD using React, Redux, .NET Core.
- Designed and develop Restful api using .NET core to handle CRUD action.
- Implementing the data access layer using Entity Framework Code First approach and writing gueries using LINQ to Entity for data retrieval.
- Integrated 3rd party api such as bing map and Twilio.
- Design and develop ticketing system from scratch for QA department using ASP.NET MVC, JQuery, Bootstrap to help the team to track issue.
- Develop calibration system that used VB into C#, Windows Form.

Environtment: Visual Studio, .NET framework, C#, ASP .NET MVC, LINQ, HTML, Javascript, Git, Azure Devops, React, .NET Core, Microsoft Azure

Analyst Programmer (Software Developer)

Teknomatrik Sdn Bhd

Mar 2018 - Feb 2019 (1 year)

- Involved in Design, Development and Testing of Windows application using ASP.NET and .NET Framework.
- · Gather requirement from client and participate in creating system design document to ensure the requirement are accurate.
- Consult and working with the team to improve the performance of 3D application.
- Creating and designing UI using Windows Form, .Net and Entity Framework.
- Optimizing performance on Unity 3D Engine to ensure smooth and efficient operation of 3D applications.
- Used ADO.NET for database access, query and manipulation.

Environment: ASP.NET, C#.NET, Windows Form, SQL Server, JSON, Entitty Framework, Unity Engine

Education



UNIVERSITI MALAYSIA PAHANG

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering 2013 - 2017

Universiti Teknologi MARA

foundation, Engineering

Licenses & Certifications



Scrum Master Certified (SMC) - Scrum.org

1170333

Skills

C# • Microsoft Azure • Git • .NET Core • React.js • AngularJS • Entity Framework • AngularJS